All right, well, and that's a lot of the
guys that they're like, "You're going
viral."
I was like, "What does that mean?" You
were going viral for things you've been
doing for years. [music]
It is my pleasure to be welcomed here on
the Cult Show by Cults owner and CEO
Carlie Irsay Gordon. Carlie, we're here
at the NFL owners meetings at the
Biltmore in Phoenix. I'm curious as
you've kind of gone around here, you've
talked to people, you've just been in
this space. Have you reflected on the
legacy your dad, Mr. Irsay, left on the
league? Have other people come up to you
and said like, you know, you know,
talked to you about your dad about the
legacy he left on this great league?
That's a very full question. Um, yeah,
I've got I love it. I've got lots of
answers. I mean, it's definitely
bittersweet, but I know one of the best
things is
is you guys here at our staff dinner. I
think
we're exactly where he would want us to
be, which would be carrying the torch
forward. And
yeah, he's always talked about, you
know,
being a steward
of a franchise. And
just like in our game, it's like the
next man up or woman in this case. Um
but I think that certainly being here in
Arizona at the Biltmore, I mean, the
Breakers and Palm Beach is another one
where it's just loaded with
not even just memories of what he was
doing in our business, but, you know,
growing up in this business, being the
oldest, just
all the all the memories that we have as
a family coming here
over spring break and during those
meetings. And I think my dad
you know, of course, owners here, they
love that he spoke his mind.
Um sometimes
maybe a little too much, some people
might say, but I think he always
That's one thing that I've always
respected about him and a lot of other
owners that was that he
had a different perspective and he
wasn't afraid to share it. And I think
that that's really important. Um
especially just being a consortium of 32
different clubs, I think it's really
important to have those different
perspectives. And my dad, even being,
you know, we lost him too early at 65.
But it's even funny for me being 45 and
that I've been coming to these meetings
for almost 25 years. And um
I know I'm probably close to the one of
the youngest people in the room, but
what's so interesting is I've been
coming to those meetings for a lot
longer than a lot of people in the room.
And
I think a lot of that's thanks to my dad
because he
Like I said, at a young age, I remember
being in undergrad and
going to my first meeting and he just
like sit and listen and you just
soak everything up like a sponge and see
how things work. And
it's it's just very
it's a big honor, I think, to be here.
Um
you know, carrying forward my dad's
legacy. That's great. Um
when you look at this team, let's talk
about kind of the 2026 Colts here. Um
we're we're kind of through the the
heavy part of free agency.
Obviously, there's still a lot more to
go with the draft and, you know, Chris
says the, you know, cement's not dry on
a roster, you know, well into the
season. But what excites you about the
opportunity that this team has in 2026?
So, I think getting Daniel and Alec
situated, I think that was a and the
timing of it, I think you know, Chris
did a great job getting that and staff
getting those deals done so that we
could kind of
then pivot to free agency and you know,
work with our budget cuz obviously those
are big chunks that came out of it. Um
but then also the rookie class last
year, I mean
obviously Tyler, you know,
he I mean, I knew he was going to be
amazing. Um but I still think he
exceeded expectations. But then we've
got other guys like Hunter Wooldridge,
Justin Malloy coming back.
Strader's coming back. I mean, it's um
I think it's
that part is cuz it's heartbreaking for
guys, especially their rookie year. You
know, those first few years for their
development are so it's so important. Um
and you always feel bad for guys like
that because, you know, they don't want
to fall behind and miss, you know, miss
the opportunity to develop. But I think
they've
they've taken it in stride and they've
they've actually I don't know if they
would have become friends or not, but I
feel like they're like best buddies now
because they were like the two gimpy
gimpersons, you know, having
>> [laughter]
>> to buy I mean, it's hard to be It's hard
to be part of a team when you're
injured. I mean, it's always it's um
I think it's hard to still feel like
you're a part of things and you're not
contributing. So, um I'm excited for
them. And obviously you know, people
like Durden Key, I think he'll be a
great contributor. And then, you know,
the most exciting part is
seeing what young talented people we get
um in this year's draft. For the the
continuity between Chris Ballard, Shane
Steichen, and Daniel Jones, that being
in place now, how do you envision that
trio kind of growing and and building on
the success that they had over the first
half of last season together now in
2026?
So, I think
with Chris and Shane, obviously, I think
the one of the biggest pieces I always
say is, you know, we did a regression
analysis a long time ago about, you
know, what is sort of the
I'm going to call it the kiss of death
for
where a general manager and head coach
don't succeed. And one of the things
that we found
is when you simultaneously hire them.
And when you think about it, it makes
total sense.
So, imagine hiring
one one person that has to do this,
another person, and you just like, "I
hope you get along." You know,
>> [laughter]
>> versus I think that, you know, Chris
with his tenure with us, I think it was
we were able to go out when we found
Shane and really make sure that we had
someone that complemented
Chris's style.
Um and I think I think they they have a
great relationship. Um I love working
with them. But then I think with Daniel,
too, I mean, I think some of the things
that he went through with other teams
and really finding that right chemistry
um with Shane and Shane being excited
and believing in Daniel's potential and
his ability to kind of
take his first part of his career and
really kind of take it to the next
level. And it's really, you know, it
stinks that what happened with his
injury, but I think he's
ready to hit the ball running he's hit
the ground running and just um
continue to build on the success that he
had with for the first half of the
season. I mean, you're you're so
connected with, you know, the the team
and with the coaching staff and the
players.
Was there something that you noticed
about like Shane and Daniel, maybe
if it wasn't right away, maybe like
early in the season of like, "Oh, these
two guys like really see it the same
way." And they've got that relationship
you need between a quarterback and a
coach.
Well, I mean, one of the things
and everyone that knows Shane,
which I love his weirdness, is like, you
know, he'd
go to his office and he's like, "Ooh,
I mean, you hit this guy is like
I mean, off the charts. It's like, I
sent him like this install and I come in
and he's
like,
"Oh my god, he's already like gone
through all of it. He's like, what else
I need to do What else do you have for
me to go through?" And he's like, "Okay,
I mean, he's like, this is just exactly
what I've been looking for." Just even
little
>> [cough]
>> throughout the week, you know, he'd have
these little ideas. He'd come in and
say, "Oh, I just want to make this
little tweak here in my footwork." And
he's like, "Oh, yeah, okay." I mean, I
think just
I think Daniel is a an amazing student
of the game. Um
like I said before, I mean, if you're
saying, "Okay, like on a scale of 0 to
10, 10 being like the most obsessed
person with football in the world." I
mean, Shane would be a 10.
>> He'd be a 10. And he just lives, eats,
breathes football all the time. Um
I was saying he's one of the only
coaches I know that watches college
games on the bus to our game.
Like, like, "Did you watch the Missouri
game?" And I'm like, "No, I didn't." But
I did. They probably lost.
>> [laughter]
>> That's a Missouri grad.
Um you you've told me in the past that
you prefer to say you like work with
people. That like people don't work for
you. That you're you describe yourself
as kind of like a horizontal leader.
With, you know, retaining Chris and
Shane and kind of supporting them in
this, like, how have you led
horizontally with them to support them
in kind of the charge that's been given
to replicate the success of the first 10
games of last season and then kind of
fix some of the issues that led to the
seven-game downfall? Like, how have you
supported them in those those instances?
So, I think it goes back to when you
first start off in your career or you're
kind of entry-level, I think you do
spend a lot of time listening and
observing and and honestly
going towards people that
you admire and you think they're doing a
really good job at whatever you're
aspiring to do. And so, I think with
Chris and Shane, I think
I'm still very much a student of the
game. I feel like on a good day, I might
have like fifth-grade reading level
because I can't just watch tape all day
and do everything. And that's okay cuz
that's their job. But I think that um
having
having that the trust and kind of being
in being with them long enough and just
even the meetings being able to ask
questions and debate things and not
always agree, but then I think when we
leave, a lot of times I think that's the
benefit is
a GM versus a head coach versus an
owner, we're all going to have different
perspectives. We're all going to have
different lenses that we're looking,
you know, through. And I think that's
where
I think that's where that kind of comes
down to teamwork, right? And making sure
ultimately that we're aligned. Um
but I think part of it is
the working with people is really
important because we're a football team.
And you know, I think you could say
it's not that
you know, leaders, you have to know who
the leaders are, but I also think what's
really important is being able to build
a culture where good ideas can come from
anyone from anywhere.
And I think that's part of like
when people say, you know, with
diversity, like why is diversity
important?
It's important because
your experience, whether if you're a
woman or your minority, your
socioeconomic background, your where you
came from in your career, it's the
cognitive diversity that I think is so
important. And ultimately, I think when
people have that mutual respect and
they're not thinking like, oh,
you know, well, I
I'm not, you know, a manager level, but
I have this idea or I have this thought
about I mean, even across our
business, even in ticketing, it's like
we should have a culture where
not to be
you know, disagree just to disagree and
ruffle people's feathers, but you should
be able to like I think people want to
feel like they're contributing and why
can't it
I mean, I think it would be really
not productive and not a good use
of our staff if people didn't feel like
they could just bring ideas or thoughts
about things.
I'm curious, you you brought up
the like you're sort of like a like a
fifth grade level. I think I would I
would frame that as like you're at a
really high level compared to where
Chris and Shane are in terms of their
football knowledge. Like I always view
my job as like I'm never going to be
close to their knowledge. Like if you're
at a fifth grade level, I'm in like
pre-K. But like it's knowing but it's
it's knowing what like the right
questions to ask.
As an owner, do you view that as kind of
like one of the more important tasks
that you have is just like knowing the
right questions to ask to create that
discourse to then all come together for
an answer.
Because it yes, because you have to have
I would say
a basic vocabulary, right? Around
I think I'm going back
16 to 18 years ago when it's like
first you learn the personnel groupings,
then you learn
you know, the different route concepts,
then you learn I mean, there's different
like 11 personnel and then you there's
just different or even, you know,
looking at defense and understanding the
different types of coverages and
eventually getting, you know, there's
cover two, cover three, and then you get
into the
the [__] cover five is something I can
just tell it's it looks like cover three
or three match to me sometimes, but um
sometimes too, players will also be
like, don't worry about it. It's like
it's still the rule is still this. It's
like, okay, well, I think like a
quarterback probably needs to know that.
>> [clears throat]
>> Um but I think it's about having I think
starting with the basic vocabulary so
that you can at least
like I know I've said this before, but
you need to be able to tell
when you're interviewing someone cuz
people can say a bunch of buzzwords,
but
how like they could memorize all these
things, but then how is it in action?
Like how is it when it's applied?
Because ultimately, what it is is
you could have the most amazing
schemes and an install thing, but like
A, if it's too many plays in an install
a week and the players are like, wow,
this is a lot different than what we
installed in OTAs. It's like, well, if
we don't have time to actually practice
it and
inculcate it into the system and be
ready for it, then sometimes it has to
be that balance of like, okay, this is
an idea that we should maybe we should
have looked at this in training camp.
You know, versus I think that's the key
is it's easy, especially in offense
sometimes, the whole paralysis by
analysis where
cuz you get to attack, so it's kind of
like
you can over scheme sometimes, but
again, like I think I'm just there
generally
to
see how the you can tell when the system
is being stressed in a certain way.
Yeah.
Um
last off season, I went through like a
phase. I spent like a week just like
watching YouTube videos on protections
cuz I was like, this is something I
don't know enough about.
>> so hard. It's yeah. I was like, oh my
god, I don't know how
>> like offensive linemen are like the
rocket science science level of and just
even like the angle of their foot in a
pass progression. I mean, it's um
>> the tiny little details.
What's something you've like dug into
maybe over the last couple of months or
even the last year or so
um just of like, you know, hey, this is
something I really want to dig into like
football wise just to kind of grow with
and you know, you have access to meeting
rooms. You can go in and you can talk to
Lou Anarumo or Brian Mason or Jim Bob
Cooter, you know, Shane, whoever. What's
like one of those things that you've
kind of just been like, I really want to
learn more about this and then you went
and like did it. What's funny you say
that, definitely protections. I need to
do that again. And I also think we're
really fortunate because
coach [clears throat] Tony is probably
one of the most He's a great teacher,
but he makes things
funny. Like he has
like we have this ooze principle where
it's like
it's almost like this combo where you
shift,
but it's like it's called ooze because
it's like
ooze, you slow the you don't you don't
like shift as fast as like another
another player, but it'll be like when
you're watching tape of them, I'm like,
and now we
or he'll say, you know, like there's
certain like certain big plays with
Quentin, he's like, look at that. He has
all these sound effects that actually
makes it very entertaining and fun to
learn because it's you spend a lot long
hours in there. Um
And then I would say, you know,
obviously like special teams cuz you
know, we've changed some of the rules,
but continuing to
look at look at that in special teams,
how we coach it, and even just how
we
utilize personnel in certain weeks when
guys have to come in and out and just
getting a better understanding of that.
I feel like that's always an area
like I enjoy learning cuz it's
it's hard to be a special teams
coordinator, especially when you get
into the season and
you know, sometimes you won't find out,
you know, it's like we had one time
where it's like, why do we only have
so many guys on the field? What happened
to the other guys? Like someone got hurt
and someone forgot to tell them and then
they didn't do the substitution. So I
mean, it's a
there's a lot of coordination for them
and a kind of thinking of, okay, and if
if this happens, then what? If the you
know what I mean? There's a lot of
scenarios they have to run through.
Um so that's definitely another area.
Um and then just continuing
obviously like the quarterback,
just continuing to see how they
just from their footwork to their the
progressions to me are so fascinating
because um
like to me, I'm also like, okay, if it's
like this is a one, two, three
progression and a lot Frank would say
like, you kind of think about it like a
triangle and I'm like, I remember
telling Matt Ryan, I was like, but that
doesn't look like a triangle.
And he's like, well, I mean, generally,
it's kind of like a triangle. It's it's
just it's so it's just um
and then I would say TCU coverage is
another one you should research cuz that
one's
most quarterbacks will tell you it's a
pain in the ass. This is great because
I'm glad you you said like I should
should research because the only reason
why I asked that question is cuz I was
like, I need stuff for me to research.
So I was like, I know I'm going to I'm
going to pick Carly's brain of like,
what have you been looking up because
you know what you're looking for. And
now great, now I have like three things
I'm going to research.
>> Rushing. That's one I just I it doesn't
hit my brain. But I think it's also this
is where this is where kind of the magic
of coaching working synergistically with
the player because like Taimatu like
Jaylen Taimatu,
which I I'm going to go on record as his
mom told me because everyone calls him
JT, but his name isn't JT. Okay.
>> It's actually Jaylen.
Okay.
>> So it's kind of a funny thing, but
everyone keeps calling him JT and I'm
like, do you want to correct them?
He's like,
I mean, they've just been calling me
this for so long. I'm just going to like
let it go.
It's kind of like Bobby Okereke.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> When he would I mean, everyone's calling
him Okereke for like and I said, why
don't you say anything?
He's like, oh, I you know, I didn't want
to No. Um so
What was it Wait, what was the question
we were talking about again? It was more
of just like, thank you for giving me
things to like look up and go go
research. Um
I want to do something fun here. So like
last year, you were kind of the
recipient of quite a bit of attention on
social media. You were kind of like a
social media star last year. Like
>> Yeah, that's what I've heard. Yeah, I I
imagine I I know you don't have a
Twitter account. I have one, but it's
like
in stasis.
It's encased in blue [laughter] sight.
Um
>> [clears throat]
>> But like did did your kids come to you
or like did people come to you and be
like like look at this. Like you're
you're going viral for some of the
things, but it you were going viral for
things you'd been doing for years. I
well, that's what a lot of the guys
said. They're like, you're going viral.
I was like, what does that mean?
>> [laughter]
>> And Tyquan O'Groves, they're like, no,
I'm serious. And I don't know. I mean,
it's one of those things where
my biggest my biggest concern was always
like, I don't want to be a distraction
to the guys. And
that was one of the things I asked, you
know,
I still have a lot to learn down here
and they're like, why would they not
They're like, why would you be a
distraction? They're like, this is what
you've always done. So I don't know. I
think that's one of those things that's
interesting where all of a sudden I feel
like in a lot of ways, I'm doing the
same job I did before,
but for whatever reason, you know, I
think when your title changes,
>> Right. you know, I guess the buck does
stop with me. So I mean, the the TV
cameras
focus over to you a little bit more,
which then leads to, if you don't mind,
I have a couple of printouts here.
It leads to
um
certain reactions.
So, let's start with this one, which
we're going to splash up on the screen
on YouTube. If you're If you're
listening to this, um
know that these are just some
screenshots that we pulled out. So,
do you remember this one?
>> [laughter]
>> Yes, I heard about this one.
What uh What What's going on there?
Um
so,
I was charting
and a play was called. I believe it was
third down.
And
I thought I had a pretty good poker
face, but I probably need to keep
working on that.
>> [laughter]
>> Um
so, I guess I did have a little bit of
an opinion
about the play that was called
and my eyebrows showed my opinion.
>> [laughter]
>> But you never know. Like that We were in
other games where it's like, okay, well,
that worked, but it was kind of like one
of those things where I was like, mhm
I'm not sure how this is going to play
out. But like when you have those
opinions, like uh you're not then going
to Shane or even like on it. You're not
talking on the headset and being like,
what are you doing? Like
you you aren't like
articulating that in the moment. It's
>> No. No.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Absolutely not. But then it's like on
Monday, I think you're and I think
here's the thing that's You're bringing
up a good point and it's part of what we
were talking about earlier where
when I think you have a healthy system
where
you observe something and it's sort of
out of in a classical sense of maybe the
way that
you would
be progressing through
down and distance and where you are and
what you're supposed to do and what the
analytics people tell you to do. I think
one of the things that Shane does really
well is I would chart this and then say,
"Hey,
you know, what was I thinking here?"
>> Mhm.
Not like, how dare you do that? How dare
you run the ball on third and long?
>> with curiosity, not judgment.
>> Yeah, and his his and
I think the part where
you can kind of go, is this red flag is
when if someone can't explain to you why
they tried something different that's
out of the ordinary, then that's a
little bit like, mhm
what were you really thinking? Were you
just being impulsive? Were you just
feeling desperate? Like you had no
freaking clue what to do and you're just
like, I'm just going to
throw this out there and see if it
sticks. Versus I think the best thing
about Shane is he's like, well,
we had looked at this scheme against
this team
and I was thinking ahead to the next
thing and I just thought, okay, this had
worked
with some other riskier game that I I
just figured we'd
in a couple other series, we'd done
something different and I didn't want
them to think, okay, now they know what
we're going to do and so
that's why I tried this and I was like,
that makes total sense. But sometimes,
you know what I mean? Sometimes you have
to try new ideas and they don't always
work and sometimes you try a new idea
and you're like, wow. I mean Yeah.
All right, I got another one here. This
is This is a fun one. This wasn't from a
TV broadcast.
But this is from the Colts bar in
Berlin.
So,
with this one,
I think
I got to give kudos to my dad because I
think that was
I was there with Pete Ward our CEO and
>> [clears throat]
>> I think you know, when you're in Germany
in Berlin and you were there and
I think part of the fun is going to
going to a bar and meeting different
fans, meeting fans from Germany and you
know, it's kind of like to me it just
seemed like a culturally appropriate
thing to do would be to buy
everyone there around a drinks for
showing up to our event and um
those are like the little things I feel
like my what my dad would always do
because I feel like it's you know, just
uh everyone's having fun and
I think the the event that we hosted
there with It went
>> It was amazing.
>> Yeah. Just the fervor and the energy and
the passion of all the fans from Berlin.
So, it just seemed very appropriate
>> Yeah. to buy the round of drinks, but
don't ask me to say it in German again
cuz I won't. Yeah. Well, you you
practiced some German before you got on
stage with me and I was just like, that
is going out in front of a bunch of
people and speaking in German, a lot of
whom speak German.
That was That was impressive. That's
very impressive. All right, one more
here.
This is kind of the the This is the
classic one. The last one. It's for our
listeners, it's your your arms are
raised up in the air signaling a
touchdown.
I think that was from week one.
Yes, it was from week one.
What was What was going on there? So,
I think
like I said, I'm try I think my poker
face looks pretty good there.
>> Mhm.
But I think
honestly,
part of the fun of our game is it's
emotional and I try to I always like to
take Gilly stuff on Gilmore's his his
secret to success was always like, don't
get too high, don't get too low. So, it
just seemed like, okay, this is a way to
Mhm. sort of silently celebrate without
you know, going crazy.
>> Mhm.
Um
but it honestly just kind of like
like it was almost like a
just a reaction that happened and I I
don't like honestly until
someone showed me this, I didn't even
realize that I had done that.
>> [laughter]
>> That's great.
>> So, yeah. All right, I got one more and
uh it's the same pose,
but it is um Colts wide receiver Kemon
Owens dressed up as you for the Colts
Halloween party. I mean, he looks better
than me in this outfit, in my opinion.
And his kudos to Kemon's wife
because
I mean, he had the wig, he had the same
I mean, the glasses look similar. I
mean, it was
and I don't even know where he would
find a dress
with like if you're like ripped here.
I'm like, how did he even Where did he
find Where did she find a dress that
would fit a professional athlete?
Yeah, it's it's it's that I I'm going to
have to have him on the podcast and get
to the bottom of that, too. No, I mean,
he had it everything down like even to
the hat. Like he had the hat, the
glasses and the
that dress with buttons and then like
this white little dickie thing. I don't
even know.
It was amazing. I mean, there were like
kids dressed up as you for Halloween,
too. Not just like your own players, but
like kids walking around. I saw a couple
come to my house trick-or-treating. You
did?
>> Yeah. I mean, honestly, that was one of
the things that really
made
cuz as Chris will say, I'm like I'm more
of a stoic, non-emotional person, but
that really
um
>> [clears throat]
>> resonated with me because the fact that
little girls are dressing up like me was
kind of um
was kind of blown away, honestly. I
don't know why they would be doing
[clears throat] that, but it definitely
it was definitely like, wow, I can't
that's kind of amazing.
Needless to say, they got extra candy at
the Stankovits household. They did?
Yeah. I was like, take as much as you
want. This is great.
>> [laughter]
>> There was one kid who showed up like
this is a couple years ago. He showed up
in a Dikembe Mutombo jersey and I was
just like, take everything. It's an
incredible incredible thing. Um All
right, which brings me to the last thing
we're going to do cuz I just remembered
a guy, Dikembe Mutombo.
Um one of my favorite things to do,
Carly, is play the Immaculate Grid. You
ever seen these before?
No. So, it is
uh
it I did this with Daniel Jones. So,
listeners of the pod viewers of the pod
know I I did this with DJ.
So, which he's probably way better than
me. Well, so Daniel Daniel used uh one
of our categories was Duke played in
March Madness and he used his brother,
Huh.
Bates Jones, which was like I was like,
that's amazing. That's amazing. Probably
like .0001%
of people would have used Bates Jones.
But the goal of this is you can't use
the same player twice and you need to
um
you know, kind of
like it's just a great opportunity to
remember some players, you know, your
favorite players, favorite Colts,
favorite guys from around the NFL. So,
let's start with the the first one
there. A player who played for the Colts
and a player who played for the U,
University of Miami.
So, that one is that one is is
definitely an easy one, Reggie. Reggie
Wayne. There are a lot of guys who could
go there. Um
but Reggie Wayne's a good one there.
Now, you do have
played for the played for Miami and had
a thousand yard receiving season. You
already used Reggie Wayne.
You can't use him again.
So, we could use another person that
played for us.
Albeit too briefly, Andre Johnson.
That's right. He had that one year with
the Colts, 2015.
>> too. That's great.
Uh Hall of Famer?
Reggie's roommate in college.
>> Mhm.
Ed Reed.
For uh that would be Hall of Famer. And
for Miami. And he has amazing straw
hats.
I mean, Reggie and Ed Reed as roommates
is like Can you imagine them as
roommates? I
That's insane.
I mean, they should two Hall two should
be Hall of Famers there. One right now,
obviously, but I know. Hopefully Reggie
gets in soon. Um
God, those Miami teams were stacked.
Um all right.
Let's move down to the next row. Um play
>> against IU. Well, yeah, not against IU.
Did you go to that? It was so fun.
I saw it was so crazy. A fan
in front of us
and actually, he's like a partner, I
think at Ice Miller. So, he's like
probably
I don't know, in his early 50s,
but he was so moved
that he ripped off the seat
at the stadium and took it home with
him.
And I was I was just thinking
you know, and then just people
like I said, how many years
you would know this, but I know it's
decades. How many years was people from
IU
I mean, the alumni base and just like
adult men just cry sobbing, openly
sobbing and
and hugging each other.
>> Yeah.
It was just It was such an incredible
That's amazing. game to be there for. It
was amazing.
All right, so the next one is a played
for the Colts and played for the team
that your family initially bought, which
is the Rams.
And then was promptly traded for the
Colts in the first and only
trade of franchises in American
professional sports history, I would
assume. My grandpa used to say it got
decided in a poker game.
>> [laughter]
>> Not sure if that's true, but he he was
good at telling lots of tall tales and
some of you just never knew [laughter]
which one was true and which one wasn't.
>> [gasps]
>> So, I would go with Eric Dickerson. A
great football player in the Colts Ring
of Honor. And that was the that was one
of the big trades your dad executed.
When he started off as GM was trading
for Eric Dickerson.
>> excited about it. Made the playoffs.
First playoff appearance with the Colts
there. Um next one up would be played
for the Rams and had a thousand-yard
receiving season. It's kind of testing
your football history knowledge here.
I'm going to go with
Isaac Bruce. Isaac Bruce, good player.
Greatest show on turf Rams, those were
those were like my those were like my
formative years watching football.
>> Really? Yeah, those were like the
coolest teams ever. Those were my guys.
>> like I'll just never forget Jerome
Bettis. Mhm. The the earlier Rams.
>> on the field before the game and just
seeing like
going and standing next to him. Cuz I
remember when I was working more in
scouting, too. It's like same thing with
like Von Miller cuz you watch Von Miller
on TV and it's like he doesn't really
look that big. And I remember one of our
scouts at the time was like, "Just go
stand by him and see if you still feel
that way."
>> [clears throat]
>> And I was like, "He's actually really
big."
>> Yeah.
I'm taking that back.
>> [laughter]
>> DeForest Buckner's like that. We're
like, "Buck is Buck's a big guy." But
like when he's got his pads on and
walking by you're like
Well, and like the joke is I was joking
with him his hands are dinner plates cuz
you know a dinner plate is 11 in.
So, it's like his hand is the size of a
dinner plate.
>> I believe Lara Overton once referred to
his hands as being dinner plates on a
previous Colts podcast. So, shout out to
Lara.
>> Yeah. It's accurate.
>> It's true. Um the last one here played
for the Rams and is in the Pro Football
Hall of Fame.
Uh one of the greatest underdogs.
Kurt Warner.
Great great quarterback.
That I mean that night that the What was
that? The '99 Rams team?
Yeah, that was like
It was an amazing story, too.
>> Yeah, right. Stocking shelves.
He was great at bagging groceries and
throwing the ball. Yeah, those are two
skills I'm not very good at.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh all right, then last one here is
played for the Colts and had a
thousand-yard rushing season for the
Colts. Mhm.
Jahvid Best. Jahvid Best, yeah.
I mean you you could There are a lot of
options there. Frank Gore, Jonathan
Taylor obviously, Marlon Mack in recent
years.
Um and then this is a tough one. So, a
thousand-yard rushing season and in the
same season also had a thousand
receiving yards. There are only three
players who've done it in NFL history.
That is an amazing feat, but
this one I would say is
it's easy because he's just a freak
athlete, Christian McCaffrey.
>> Yes. He's the most recent one to do it.
Marshall Faulk and Roger Craig are the
other two. When did Roger Craig play?
He would have been
what? In the '80s? '80s? Roger Craig?
Steve Campbell's nodding his head.
That's good cuz I was like yeah, I think
it was a little before my time. But a
Hall of Famer this year. That's amazing.
He'll be He'll be a part of that class
as well with with Adam Vinatieri. And
then the last one there
is a thousand rushing yards and is in
the Pro Football Hall of Fame. So, this
is literally any running back.
Well, then I have to go with one of my
favorite ones then, Edgerrin James.
Is he Is he like one of the coolest Colt
Colts to ever come through
our organization?
Well, yes. And I'll I'll never forget,
too, because it's like I remember my dad
saying
he grew up like
like his workout routine is absurd.
Like but then in the summers he's just
like in this like foot Cuz my dad hated
anything hot. Like he would like to go
outside like where we are in Arizona
now.
>> [clears throat]
>> But then he'd have to come in and you
know
the the hilarious story my sisters will
all agree that
our windows like when we were growing up
in the summer would be like fogged up
because he would turn it down to like
55°.
And my mom actually like had one of the
contractors set it so that he could like
turn it down to like he turned it down
to like 42 and it was but it was like
governed so it would just really only go
down to like 63. But he'd be like
>> [laughter]
>> But he would so like he said Edgerrin
James should be just like out picking
watermelons.
And I'd be like, "I mean that probably
would put I can't even like watermelons
are huge. I can't imagine
like farming watermelons
by hand."
All right, well that's a great job on
that grid, Carlie. Like
>> excellent ball knowledge
on it. I mean
>> as good as Daniel I'm sure, though.
Daniel Daniel was really good. He was
really Pete Ward would win probably the
>> would snap everyone. the company-wide
challenge for this. But
>> that's just cuz he has more Colts
knowledge than probably any human on the
planet.
>> Mhm. He's a walking encyclopedia. John
Scott, our retired
equipment manager, would also
>> Yeah. He's very good at jersey numbers.
He can remember them.
>> Mhm. So many. Yeah, I can do that for
like I do I do the grid, but I can do it
with like White Sox players, which is a
completely useless skill for anyone
except me
when I do the baseball one. And then it
just turns into like, "Who am I doing
this for?" other than like, "Ah, I
remember that guy. That was great."
That's hilarious. Just sitting here
remembering guys. All right, Carlie
Irsay Gordon, thank you for the time
here on the podcast. Really appreciate
it and
look forward to the next [music] one at
the next owners meetings. Thanks, JJ.